<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="ossia.logger" module="Ossia" category="Ossia">

	<digest>
		Logger
	</digest>

	<description>
		Logger
	</description>

	
	<!--METADATA-->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Ossia</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Ossia</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Network</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	
	<!--INLETS-->
	<inletlist>
			<inlet id="0" name="Message input" type="any">
			<digest>Messages to ossia.model</digest>
			<description>Messages to the node</description>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>


	<!--OUTLETS-->
	<outletlist>
	</outletlist>

	<!--METHODS-->	
	<methodlist>
		<method name="error">
			<arglist/>
			<digest>
				Send an error message to the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sending the (error) message with some content afterwards will send the content as an error message to the connected log server
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="trace">
			<arglist/>
			<digest>
				Send a trace message to the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sending the (trace) message with some content afterwards will send the content as a trace message to the connected log server
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="info">
			<arglist/>
			<digest>
				Send an info message to the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sending the (info) message with some content afterwards will send the content as an info message to the connected log server
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="warning">
			<arglist/>
			<digest>
				Send a warning message to the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sending the (warning) message with some content afterwards will send the content as a warning message to the connected log server
			</description>
		</method>
		
		<method name="critical">
			<arglist/>
			<digest>
				Send a critical message to the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sending the (critical) message with some content afterwards will send the content as a critical message to the connected log server
			</description>
		</method>

		<method name="debug">
			<arglist/>
			<digest>
				Send a debug message to the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sending the (debug) message with some content afterwards will send the content as a debug message to the connected log server
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

		
	
	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->
	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="host" get="1" set="1" type="atom" size="1">
			<digest>
				URL of the log server
			</digest>
			<description>
				The <at>@host</at> attribute allows to define the URL of the log server to feed.
			</description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name="appname" get="1" set="1" type="atom" size="1">
			<digest>
				Name of this application
			</digest>
			<description>
				The <at>@appname</at> attribute allows to give a textual name to this application. This can be useful for humans to identify it on the server side.
			</description>
		</attribute>

		<attribute name="heartbeat" get="1" set="1" type="int" size="1">
			<digest>
				Set heartbeat interval in seconds
			</digest>
			<description>
				The <at>@heartbeat</at> attribute allows determine at which rate (in seconds) the "alive" message will be sent to the log server.
			</description>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>
	

	<!--SEEALSO-->
	<seealsolist>
	</seealsolist>

	
</c74object>
